Se Yeon Hwang

Department of Physics, University of Seoul, Seoul, 02504, Republic of Korea Phone + 82 1024138638 Email worldhsy@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I have a strong interest in **Cosmology and Large Scale Structure** of the Universe. I worked on utilizing **statistical techniques** and **machine learning algorithms** to extract information from observation and simulation data. I thrive on presenting my findings and engaging with colleagues, all while striving to establish the identity of my research.

EDUCATION

Post-graduate Researcher University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea	Sep.2023 - Current
Physics, MSc (GPA: 4.35/4.5)	Sep.2021 - Aug.2023
University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea	
• Thesis topic : Applying Transformer Algorithms to Large Scale Structure	
Physics, BSc (GPA: 3.85/4.5)	Mar.2017 - Aug.2021
University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea	
 Double major in Entrepreneurship 	
High School Diploma	Mar.2014 - Feb.2017
YangJu High School, Gyeonggi-do, Republic of Korea	
 Natural Sciences Curriculum with an emphasis on Physics and Chemistry 	

RESEARCH

Independent Research

• *Project*: team SCOPE (Structure-based Cosmological Parameter Estimation)

Sep.2023 - Current

- o Member: Dr. Cristiano G. Sabiu, Young Ju, Hannah Jhee, Sumi Kim
- *About*: Studying the effect of Large Scale Structure Components when Estimating Cosmological Parameters with Machine Learning Algorithms

Graduate Research

 Project: team CLML (Cosmology with Large scale structure using Machine Learning)

Jan.2022 - Aug.2023

- o Academic Supervisor: Dr. Cristiano G. Sabiu, Prof. Inkyu Park
- About : Predicting Cosmological parameters using Machine learning with simulations
- Awards: Poster Award at 2022 105th Korean Astronomical Society spring meeting
- o ArXiv: 2304.08192 (Accepted in JCAP, Confirmed Date: 30 Oct.2023)

- *Project*: team CHOA (Cosmology with Higher Order Astrostatistics) Sep.2021 - Dec.2021 o Academic Supervisor: Dr. Cristiano G. Sabiu, Prof. Inkyu Park • About: Estimating Cosmological parameters with n-point correlation functions **Undergraduate Research** • *Project*: team CHOA (Cosmology with Higher Order Astrostatistics) Mar.2021-Aug.2021 o Academic Supervisor: Dr. Cristiano G. Sabiu, Prof. Inkyu Park o About: Studying 2,3,4-point correlation functions with SDSS CMASS data *Project*: HAWC (the High-Altitude Water Cherenkov Observatory) Dec.2020-Jun.2021 o Academic Supervisor: Prof. Chang Dong Rho o About: Studying High-Mass Micro Quasars (Cyg X-1, Cyg X-3) o *ArXiv*: 2108.00594 (ICRC 2021 conference paper) **PRESENTATIONS Invited Speaker** "Opening the Black Box: Interpretable Machine Learning in Astronomy" 20 Oct.2023 presented at 2023 108th Korean Astronomical Society fall meeting **Oral Presentations** "Constraining Cosmology using Self-Attention" presented at Workshop for 03 Nov.2022 Korea-UK AI/ML Research in Fundamental Sciences "Cosmology with Self-Attention Algorithms" presented at 10th Korea Institute 18 Oct.2022 for Advanced Study Workshop on Cosmology and Structure Formation
- **Poster Presentations**
- "Deep Learning Approaches to Large Scale Structure" presented at 2022
 General Assembly International Astronomical Union
 (Poster Awards) "Comparing Cosmological Information from Deep Learning and Higher Order statistics" presented at 105th Korean Astronomical Society spring meeting

12 Oct.2022

30 Aug.2023

"Predicting Cosmological Parameters using CNN and ViT from Large Scale

Structure" presented at 106th Korean Astronomical Society fall meeting

Korea Astronomy Machine Learning meeting

"Exploring Two algorithms in Cosmology: CNN and ViT" presented at 9th

- "Detecting the Baryon Acoustic Oscillations in the N-point correlation functions of SDSS Galaxies" presented at 104th Korean Astronomical Society fall meeting
- "Cosmology with Higher Order Astrostatistics" presented at 103th Korean
 Astronomical Society spring meeting

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Teaching and Mentoring Experiences	
• Teaching Assistant for lab class, General Physics Experiment for undergraduate for 4 semesters	Sep.2021-Jun.2023
• Tutoring Mathematics for Middle and High School Students	Jan.2021-Jun.2021
• Teaching Assistant for elective course, Man, Universe and Civilization for 2 semesters	Sep.2020-Jul.2021
• Teaching English and Science Classes for Middle and High School Students at a Private Academy (at G1230FC and Hanssem Academy)	Jun.2019-Oct.2019
• Tutoring Science Experiments for Middle School Students	Jan.2019-Apr.2019
 Mentoring for Multicultural North Korean Defector at Sangmyeong Elementary School 	Mar.2018-Jun.2018
Courses on Coding	
• Special Lectures on Computational Physics (Graduate)	Sep.2021-Dec.2021
• Special Topics in Machine Learning Physics (Graduate)	Mar.2021-Jun.2021
• Fundamentals of Programming (Undergraduate)	Mar.2021-Jun.2021
• Visualization and Physics (Undergraduate)	Sep.2020-Dec.2020
• Physics and Computer II (Undergraduate)	Sep.2017-Dec.2017
• Physics and Computer I (Undergraduate)	Mar.2017-Jun.2017
Summer Schools	
• GMT summer school (1st and 2nd prize in team project)	21-25 Aug.2023
ALMA summer school	1-4 Aug.2023
 KIAS summer school 2023 Extragalactic and cosmology 	18-26 Jul.2023
Gravitational Waves and Numerical Relativity Winter School	17-21 Jan 2022
• KIAS summer school 2021 Extragalactic and cosmology (online)	19-23 Jul.2021
Scholarships	
• Scholarship for Undergraduate Research Assistant	Sep.2020-Aug.2021
• Received Korea Student Aid Foundation Scholarship for 8 semesters	Mar.2017-Aug.2021
 Korea Student Aid Foundation Scholarship for Multicultural North Korean Defector Mentoring 	Mar.2018-Jun.2018